Guide to the Turnpikes Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Turnpikes collection
1790-1898
MS 1063
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7
The collection consists of correspondence, minutes of meetings, and business and financial records for the Tenth Massachusetts Turnpike Company, the New London and Lyme Turnpike Company, the Derby Turnpike Company, the Hartford and New Haven Turnpike Company, and the Hartford and Worcester Railroad Turnpike Company.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, minutes of meetings, and business and financial records for the Tenth Massachusetts Turnpike Company, the New London and Lyme Turnpike Company, the Derby Turnpike Company, the Hartford and New Haven Turnpike Company, and the Hartford and Worcester Railroad Turnpike Company.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Business; Toll roads -- Connecticut; Transportation -- Connecticut; Connecticut -- Commerce; New England -- Commerce; Derby Turnpike Company (Conn.); Farmington River Company; Hartford and Albany Turnpike; Hartford and New-Haven Turnpike Company; Hartford and Worcester Railroad Turnpike Company; New London and Lyme Turnpike Company; Tenth Massachusetts Turnpike Company
- Inventory
  - The Tenth Massachusetts Turnpike Company [business papers], 1797-1898, undated (Box 1)
  - New London and Lyme Turnpike Company
    - Bills, orders, receipts, 1810-1828 October (Box 2)
    - Bills, orders, receipts, 1828 November-1845 (Box 3)
    - Ledger, 1853 (Box 3)
    - Stock purchases and transfers, 1810-1829 (Box 3)
    - Stock purchases and transfers, 1830-1852 (Box 4)
    - Commuter passes, 1831-1832 (Box 4)
  - Derby Turnpike Company
    - Correspondence, 1790-1897, undated (Box 5)
    - Bank books, 1878-1897 (Box 5)
    - Clippings, 1894, undated (Box 5)
    - Profiles, undated (Box 5)
    - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1800-1845 (Box 6)
    - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1846-1897 (Box 7)
  - Hartford and New Haven Turnpike Company [toll book], 1838-1854 (Box 7)
  - Hartford and Worcester Railroad Turnpike Company
    - Minutes of meetings [photostatic copies], 1834-1835 (Box 8)
    - Report, 1835 (Box 8)
    - Map, undated (Box 8)